### **BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH**

NAME: Diaby, Moustapha

eRA COMMONS USER NAME (credential, e.g., agency login): N/A

POSITION TITLE: Associate Professor, Head of Research and Partnership Department, DRIT, ESATIC

### **EDUCATION/TRAINING**

INSTITUTION AND LOCATION	DEGREE	Completion Date	FIELD OF STUDY
INRIA Lille Nord-Europe & Université de Lille 1, France	Ph.D	2013	Computer Science
University of Orléans, France.	M.Sc.	2009	Statistics and Operations Research
Université d'Abidjan-Cocody, Côte d'Ivoire	DEA	2007	Mathematics/Statistics
Université d'Abidjan-Cocody, Côte d'Ivoire	B.Sc.	2005	Applied Mathematics/Statistics and Probability

### A. Personal Statement

My journey is a vibrant blend of teaching and research, reflecting my passion for both. Currently serving as an Associate Professor at ESATIC, I actively participate in both teaching and leadership roles, holding the position of Head of the Research and Partnership Department under the DRIT. During my tenure as an Assistant Professor at the University of Lille 1 IUT-A, I further solidified my dedication to guiding students through transformative projects. My research and teaching interests span diverse areas, including Operations Research, Operations Management, Machine Learning, Network Optimization, and Decision Support. These interests underscore my commitment to contributing to both the theoretical and practical aspects of these fields.

## **B. Professional Appointments and Accomplishments**

### **Positions and Employment**

- 2014: Research and Teaching Assistant at ESATIC
  - Head of Research and Partnership Department, DRIT Esatic
  - Associate Professor Lecturer of Rank A.
  - Computer Programming and Applied Mathematics.
- 2013-2014: Research Engineer at Ad OptiMax
  - Project Development Manager within the group.
- 2011-2013: Assistant Professor at the University of Lille 1 IUT-A, Lille, France
  - Teaching computer science subjects (Object-oriented Programming, Operating Systems, System Architecture, Statistics, Graph Theory).
  - Supervision of students: Guided projects.
- 2009-2012: Junior R&D Researcher at the National Institute for Research in Computer Science (INRIA), Lille, France
  - Modeling of Transport problems.

- Multi-objective approach.
- Consideration of revenue management approach and customer relationship management.
- Proposal and implementation of several exact and heuristic solutions.
- Publication and dissemination of research results in international scientific journals.
- 2008-2009: Software Development at Nord Sud Transit, Paris, France
  - Participation in the development of inventory management software.
  - Optimal management of transportation flows.
  - Consideration of customer relationship management.

# Other Experience and Professional Memberships

Since 2020 Member of the Rotary Club-Biétry Abidjan Cl.

Since 2010 Volunteer for mentoring youth from underprivileged areas at Afev.

Since 2011 Member of Action Against Hunger (Lille).

#### C. Selected Publications

- 1. Koivogui, Moussa & Ndiaye, Ameth & **Moustapha, Diaby**. (2022). WEIERSTRASS FORMULA FOR MINIMAL SURFACES IN SPECIAL THREE-DIMENSIONAL δ-LORENTZIAN TRANS SASAKIAN MANIFOLD. 11. 140-148.
- 2. Djanan, Attougbre & **Moustapha, Diaby** & Coulibaly, Adama. (2022). Energy and Spectral Efficiency Optimization Methods in 5G Massive Mimo Systems. Journal of Advances in Mathematics and Computer Science. 44-56. 10.9734/jamcs/2022/v37i630460.
- 3. Ousmane, Berte & **Moustapha**, **Diaby** & Adama, Coulibaly. (2021). Genetic Algorithm for the Pick-up and Delivery Problem with Time Window by Multi-Compartment Vehicles. Transport and Telecommunication Journal. 22. 343-352. 10.2478/ttj-2021-0027.
- 4. Ousmane, Berté & **Moustapha, Diaby** & Adama, Coulibaly. (2021). MULTI-COMPARTMENT VEHICLES FOR MULTI-DEPOTS PICKUP AND DELIVERY PROBLEMS WITH TIME WINDOWS. Far East Journal of Applied Mathematics. 109. 49-66. 10.17654/AM109010049.
- 5. Koua, Brou & **Moustapha**, **Diaby** & Koivogui, Moussa. (2021). MULTIPLE TRIPS VRPTW AND PDPTTW APPLIED TO THE POSTE-CI ENTERPRISE. Far East Journal of Applied Mathematics. 109. 81-101. 10.17654/AM109010081.
- 6. Bi, Kaye & **Moustapha, Diaby** & Koivogui, Moussa & Oumtanaga, Souleymane. (2021). A Memetic Algorithm for an External Depot Production Routing Problem. Algorithms. 14. 27. 10.3390/a14010027.
- 7. **Moustapha, Diaby** & Koua, Brou & Soro, Etienne. (2020). A Dial-a-Ride Problem Applied to Saharan Countries: The Case of Taxi Woro-Woro. Open Journal of Optimization. 09. 138-147. 10.4236/ojop.2020.94010.
- 8. Bi, Kaye & **Moustapha**, **Diaby** & N'Takpé, Tchimou & Oumtanaga, Souleymane. (2020). Managing an External Depot in a Production Routing Problem. International Journal of Advanced Computer Science and Applications. 11. 10.14569/IJACSA.2020.0110242.
- 9. Soro, Etienne & **Moustapha, Diaby** & Pacôme, Brou. (2018). Approches exacte et heuristique pour un problème Bi-niveau de transport longue distance de marchandises. Afrique Science Revue Internationale des Sciences et Technologie. 14. 269-284.
- 10. Etienne, Soro & Pacôme, Brou & **Moustapha, Diaby** & Asseu, Olivier & Aka, Boko & Konaté, Adama & Oumtanaga, Souleymane. (2016). Assigning eNode B to Switches in LTE Advanced Network by an Approach Genetic. Journal of Applied Sciences. 16. 549-561. 10.3923/jas.2016.549.561.

Complete List of Published Work on ResearchGate: Moustapha Diaby